[male voice in alien language]
Power over Spice is power over all
[suspenseful music playing]
[Irulan] Imperial Diary.
Year 10,191. Third comment.
The battle for Arrakis
took everyone by surprise.
There were no witnesses.
[somber music playing]
The Harkonnen operation
was perpetrated overnight,
without warning or
declaration of war.
By morning, the
Atreides were no more.
All died in the dark.
And the Emperor said...
nothing.
Since that night, my father
has not been the same.
Nor have I.
His inaction is difficult
for me to accept.
For, I know he loved Duke
Leto Atreides like a son.
[suspenseful music playing]
[chain clanks]
[Irulan] But my father's
always been guided
by the calculus of power.
This would not be the first time the
Harkonnens have done his dirty work.
[shouts in Harkonnen]
[Harkonnen army shouts]
In the shadows of
Arrakis lie many secrets...
but the darkest of
them all may remain.
The end of House Atreides.
[dramatic music playing]
[Paul] Sister, Father is dead.
Shouldn't you go
back to the stars,
be with him?
I'm afraid I won't have enough
time to fix things before your coming.
This world is beyond cruelty.
[breathes heavily]
[tense music playing]
[shushes]
[signing]
Enemy.
[Harkonnen soldier 1
speaking Harkonnen]
[suspenseful music playing]
[Fremen panting]
[Harkonnen soldier 1
continues speaking Harkonnen]
[Stilgar breathes heavily]
Stay here.
[mimicking bird]
[Harkonnen soldiers
speaking Harkonnen]
[signing]
Down. Right.
[Jessica panting]
[Jessica grunts]
[both panting]
[Harkonnen soldier
speaking Harkonnen]
[both panting]
[suspenseful music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
[Harkonnen squad
leader breathing heavily]
[speaking Harkonnen]
They're close.
[Paul grunts]
[speaks Harkonnen]
Do you hear that?
[Harkonnen soldier
speaking Harkonnen]
The rats are calling a worm.
[breathes heavily]
[Harkonnen soldier
speaking Harkonnen]
Worms!
[Harkonnen squad leader
speaking Harkonnen]
Unit, climb. Now!
[dramatic music playing]
[explodes]
[high frequency whirring]
[speaking Harkonnen]
Look for wormsign.
[breathing heavily]
[suspenseful music playing]
[speaking Harkonnen]
We're okay.
[bang]
[Harkonnen soldier
speaking Harkonnen]
[Harkonnen soldiers
Shields!
No Shields!
[Paul gasps, pants]
[Harkonnen soldiers
shouting in Harkonnen]
[shots fired]
[Paul and Jessica grunt, pant]
[Harkonnen lieutenant
speaking Harkonnen]
[tense music playing]
[Paul panting]
[Paul grunts]
[both shouting, grunting]
[panting]
[high pitched whirring]
[Harkonnen sniper
speaking Harkonnen]
I got you, rat.
[Jessica and
Harkonnen sniper grunt]
[Jessica shouts, grunts]
[Harkonnen sniper grunts]
[Jessica panting]
[panting]
Never stand with your
back towards the open.
How many times do I
have to tell you that, huh?
- [both panting] -
[Paul] You okay?
- Yeah.
- How 'bout her?
She's fine.
[indistinct chatter]
[grunts] They do not
usually venture this deep.
They wanna make sure
no Atreides escaped.
[Stilgar chuckles] You
think too much of yourself.
No, no, we are
in the deep desert.
Only Fremen can survive here.
They were here
for us, not for you.
[chuckles] Don't worry.
I'm taking you somewhere
they will never find us.
- [indistinct chatter]
- [whooshing]
Filthy water.
It's full of chemicals, but good
enough for cooling systems.
[Jessica gags]
Don't let it out.
- [sloshing]
- [ejects]
- You okay?
- Mm-hmm.
Don't let that out.
- [gags]
- Don't let it out!
- [Jessica vomits] -
[speaks Chakobsa]
[Jessica breathes heavily]
- [Jessica] I'm okay.
- [Paul] Are you sure?
Mm-hmm.
[breathes deeply]
You fought well...
once you woke up.
I wasn't sleeping.
[scoffs]
[Harkonnen soldier
grunts, chokes]
[Stilgar mimics bird]
[Stilgar speaking Chakobsa]
[Stilgar clicks tongue]
[indistinct talking]
[dramatic music playing]
[Paul] No, no, no. I'll do it.
[whooshing]
[tremors]
[chanting in Harkonnen]
[suspenseful music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
[chanting continues]
Lor... Lord Rabban.
Now that the spice
fields have been secured,
I strongly recommend bringing
all troops out of Fremen territories.
We're losing too
many men to the desert.
[Rabban] Rats.
[chanting continues
in the background]
- I beg your pardon?
- We're losing men to rats.
[speaking Harkonnen]
Fremen! I can't
confirm, my Lord.
Communications are
hectic in the open sands.
Your orders were to
control the whole planet.
- We are.
- I see only half of it.
[Harkonnen commander]
As you may recall,
the South is
uninhabitable, my Lord.
May I suggest you get some rest?
- [both grunt] -
Rats! Hairy rats!
Kill them! Kill
them! Kill them all!
Kill them all!
Rats! [echoes]
[suspenseful music playing]
[tense music playing]
[Stilgar communicates
gutturally]
[Fremen sentinel
communicates gutturally]
[sentinel leader
speaks Chakobsa]
[speaks Chakobsa]
He's asking why we're so late.
[continues conversing
in Chakobsa]
He thinks you're spies.
[speaking in Chakobsa]
You're not welcome here.
- [Chani] He
said... - I got that.
- Thanks.
- [Stilgar] Stay close to me. Hmm?
[speaks Chakobsa]
[suspenseful music playing]
[indistinct talking]
Sietch Tabr.
[indistinct chatter]
[speaking Chakobsa]
- [angry, indistinct shouting in
Chakobsa] - [Stilgar speaks Chakobsa]
[woman vocalizing]
[speaking in Chakobsa]
Jamis! Jamis!
[all shouting in Chakobsa]
You killed Jamis!
Spies!
Witch!
[angry, indistinct shouting]
[man speaking Chakobsa]
Stop! Stop!
They don't know what they're saying.
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
Mahdi!
[angry shouting continues]
[man] Lisan al-Gaib!
[Stilgar speaking Chakobsa]
I need your guidance
with the two foreigners.
[speaking Chakobsa]
Give them back to the desert.
[elders muttering]
I saw the signs.
[all laughing]
Again.
Stilgar, your faith is
playing tricks on you.
The Lisan al-Gaib has not
shown his face yet!
[all laughing]
He killed Jamis in a fair fight.
He speaks our language.
He will quickly learn our ways.
I'm ready to pledge my life for him.
The desert will handle his fate.
[oldest elder sighs]
[oldest elder groans,
speaks Chakobsa]
What about the woman?
[indistinct chatter]
Look how your Bene Gesserit
propaganda has taken root.
Some of them already
think I'm their messiah.
Others...
false prophet.
I must sway the non-believers.
If they follow me, we can
disrupt spice production.
That's the only way I
can get to the Emperor.
Your father didn't
believe in revenge.
[Paul] Yeah, well, I do.
[suspenseful music playing]
[indistinct whispering]
[Jessica] What is happening?
[speaking Chakobsa]
Too spicy for the foreigner?
[Fremen laughing]
[sighs]
What is it?
[Paul] There is
spice in the food.
[woman speaks Chakobsa]
[Fremen laughing]
He'll look pretty with blue eyes.
[Chani speaking Chakobsa]
Don't mock him.
He deserves our respect.
He's a good fighter.
- [scoffs]
- [Stilgar] Woman.
Come with me.
[praying watermasters
chant in Chakobsa]
To the well, our water we return.
[male watermaster
speaks Chakobsa]
We bless our brother, Jamis.
[praying watermasters
chant in Chakobsa]
[chanting continues]
[exhales deeply]
[Stilgar] Thirty-eight
million decaliters.
None of us, even dying of
thirst, would ever drink this water.
This is...
sacred.
Jamis' water.
We have a thousand such places.
When we have enough water,
the Lisan al-Gaib will
change the face of Arrakis.
He will bring back the
trees. He will bring back...
a Green Paradise.
[whispers] So many souls.
[bell rings]
[speaks Chakobsa]
[Stilgar grunts]
Never give your water away,
not even for the dead. Hmm?
Why are you showing me this?
Because you are Bene Gesserit.
Because you understand
the prophecies.
The mother of the Lisan al-Gaib
will be a Reverend Mother.
Our Reverend Mother is dying.
[whispers] You want
me to take her place?
Yes, I do.
You believe in Paul?
There are signs.
Yes.
[chanting continues
in background]
What if I would refuse?
Mmm. Then, he's
not Lisan al-Gaib,
and you have no
purpose to serve.
What else is left to do then but
to return your water to the well?
[clicks tongue] Huh.
[indistinct chatter]
[Paul] It's an honor, isn't it?
I think you should feel honored.
Well, it was a choice
between this or death,
so, you know, forgive
me if I'm not flattered.
How does one become
a Reverend Mother?
It's different from
one culture to another.
Here on Arrakis, I have no idea.
You're afraid.
Reverend Mothers are tasked
with holding the memories
of all the Reverend Mothers
that came before them,
so I'll be given centuries
of pain and sorrow.
Is it dangerous?
It's lethal for men.
That's for sure.
[Stilgar speaks Chakobsa]
[suspenseful music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[suspenseful music
continues playing]
[Jessica gasps softly]
[indistinct
whispering, chanting]
[indistinct chatter]
[group laughing]
What are you guys
laughing about?
Don't bother. [chuckles]
You don't believe in all this?
[Chani] No, we don't.
[Shishakli] These are
old Southern beliefs.
Southern beliefs?
Southern tribes believe a messiah
will come to deliver us from evil.
You don't believe
in the Lisan al-Gaib?
[Chani] We believe in Fremen.
[group speaking Chakobsa]
Amen.
You want to control people,
you tell them a messiah will come.
- Mm-hmm.
- Then they'll wait for centuries.
[Stilgar speaking Chakobsa]
Now, we must pray.
What about him?
- [Chani] Stilgar?
- Mm-hmm.
He's from the South. You
didn't notice his accent?
[Chani and Shishakli laugh]
[Stilgar praying in Chakobsa]
[sighs]
What'll happen to my mother?
[speaking in Chakobsa]
[group laughs]
She'll drink worm piss.
[Chani speaking in Chakobsa]
Not funny.
He's about to lose her.
If she's stupid enough to drink poison.
[group laughs]
[Stilgar speaking Chakobsa]
Shut up!
We are praying.
[Fremen nuns
speaking in Chakobsa]
[whispers] I must not
fear. Fear is the mind-killer.
Fear, the little death that
brings total obliteration.
I will face my fear. I will...
[Fremen nuns continue
speaking in Chakobsa]
[old watermaster
speaking Chakobsa]
Here is the Water of Life.
It frees the soul.
If you drink...
you shall die.
you may see.
[speaking Chakobsa]
Drink!
What is it?
[distorted voice] Drink!
[breathes heavily]
[indistinct whispering]
[grunts]
[gasps]
[chokes]
[pained grunts]
[gasps]
[shuddering breaths]
[pained grunts]
[gasps]
[speaking Chakobsa]
What have we done?
She is pregnant.
[gasps]
[shudders]
[angry, indistinct shouting]
[Stilgar speaking Chakobsa]
That was no miracle!
You saw it with your own eyes!
[groans]
[angry, indistinct shouting]
[Stilgar speaking Chakobsa]
The Mother of the Lisan al-Gaib
shall survive the Holy Poison.
And She did.
[angry, indistinct shouting]
As written!
Her people wrote that!
Blasphemy.
The prophecy has been accomplished.
The Mahdi must be Fremen!
[Stilgar speaking Chakobsa]
[Chani speaking Chakobsa]
Arrakis must be freed
by its own people!
She's right. She's right!
It's no miracle.
My mother was
trained to do that.
Poison transmutation is something
advanced Bene Gesserit can do.
I'm not the Mahdi.
I'm not here to lead.
I'm here to learn your ways.
Let me fight beside
you. That's all I'm asking.
[Stilgar speaking Chakobsa]
The Mahdi is too humble
to say He is the Mahdi.
Even more reason to know He is!
[Fremen speaking Chakobsa]
As written!
[Paul] How are you?
[Jessica] Better.
[Paul] How is she?
[Jessica] She was
frightened, but she's...
she's okay.
[Jessica breathes heavily]
[Jessica whispers] Paul.
She talks to me.
She believes in you.
[ominous music playing]
She says...
[speaking Chakobsa]
Kwisatz Haderach, show us the way.
You're so close now.
Only one step remains and you
will become the Kwisatz Haderach.
Only one step remains.
You must do what I did.
You must drink
the Water of Life.
And your mind, it's gon... it's
gonna open and you will see.
[speaking Chakobsa]
You will see!
The beauty and the horror!
[Stilgar] If you wanna fight
with us, first thing, you must learn
to be one with the desert.
So, here is a tent
and enough food.
I want you to cross that
small erg and come back.
Travel by night.
You know how to
use a paracompass?
- Yes.
- Oh.
[Stilgar sighs]
Anything else I should know?
Uh, beside the worms
and the Harkonnens,
beware of the trapdoor spiders.
Centipedes are very
nasty. Not the big ones.
They are harmless.
But the little ones, you have
to worry about. And... Oh!
Don't ever, ever
listen to the jinn.
- The jinn?
- Jinn.
Desert spirits.
They whisper at night.
[imitates Jinn whispering]
They, they can possess you.
Really, be careful.
They are demons.
[growls, laughs]
But it's true. Don't
listen to them.
[Stilgar grunts]
[Chani speaking Chakobsa]
He doesn't know how to cross.
Stilgar is going to get him killed.
What is he trying to prove?
[speaking Chakobsa]
What do you think?
"The Prophet shall know
the ways of the desert."
[Fremen speaking Chakobsa]
I think it's for the best.
What's this?
You care for him now?
He's not like the other strangers.
He's sincere.
[Jamis laughs, echoes]
[Paul panting]
[Paul] Jamis.
[Chani] You sandwalk
like a drunk lizard.
[chuckles]
Yeah, I'm doing
pretty good so far.
Yeah, well, you're not
even in worm territory yet.
[Chani] You have to
break up your rhythm.
Like this.
[Paul] Now, that's interesting
because in the filmbooks I've studied,
the anthropologists say, in order to
properly sandwalk, you actually have...
Never mind. Please keep going.
[soft music playing]
You know, I'm the only one who believes
you're gonna make it until summer?
Everyone else thinks you
won't make it two weeks.
If you wanna follow
us in the desert,
you need to know
how windtraps work.
So, listen to me.
They're simple, but they
require constant attention.
Uh, this right here, it
captures the moisture
and then it carries
it into that pocket.
Uh, and these are the filters.
They need to be
changed every three days.
What?
[chuckles]
Stop looking at me like that.
[Jessica] He's training
with the Fremen.
He will be back
soon. Don't worry.
Mm-hmm.
You're right. If we want
to protect your brother,
we need all the Fremen
to believe in the prophecy.
[suspenseful music playing]
We must convert the
non-believers one by one.
We need to start
with the weaker ones.
The vulnerable ones.
The ones who fear us.
[Fedaykin fighter
breathes heavily]
[Fedaykin fighter whispers]
Hey, get out of here. Go.
[Harkonnen soldiers
speaking Harkonnen]
[Fedaykin fighter
breathing heavily]
[Harkonnen soldier
speaking Harkonnen]
[blade swishing]
[Harkonnen soldiers and
Fedaykin fighters grunt]
[grunting continues]
- [Paul] You okay?
- [Chani] Yeah.
[speaking Harkonnen]
[rapid gunfire]
[Harkonnen soldier
speaking Harkonnen]
[rapid gunfire]
[Fedaykin fighter grunts]
[Chani and Paul grunt, pant]
[Fedaykin fighter and
Chani shouting in Chakobsa]
[Chani] Let's go! Move!
[both grunt]
[Paul and Harkonnen
soldier grunt]
[Chani] Load.
[Paul grunts]
[blade clanking]
[Harkonnen soldier shouts]
[Paul grunts]
[Paul] Chani!
[Chani] Reload!
[Chani] Ugh! Reload.
[Paul] Oh, watch out!
[both grunt, pant]
[Harkonnen soldier
speaking Harkonnen]
[Paul] Its shield will
only open when it fires.
[Chani] I know that. What
do you think I'm trying to do?
[Paul] I'll trigger it. On
my signal. Be ready.
[Paul] Go!
[grunts] Ah, shit!
[Paul panting]
- Go! Go!
- [rapid gunfire]
[grunts, groans]
[Harkonnen soldier screams]
[explodes]
[Chani laughs]
[dramatic music playing]
[Chani and Paul grunt]
[Fedaykin fighters cheering]
[indistinct chatter]
[Stilgar speaking Chakobsa]
You saw what he did.
He saw it coming,
and he saved her life.
He saw it.
He can foresee.
[Shishakli sniffing]
[speaking in Chakobsa]
Muad'Dib likes his smell.
[all laughing]
Who taught you
to fight like that?
- My old masters.
- Hmm.
They were close friends.
They were massacred.
Alongside my father.
You've been fighting the
Harkonnens for decades.
My family's been
fighting them for centuries.
I know everything about them.
Their habits, their ways of thinking.
You know everything
about the desert.
You harness the
very power of it.
We can stop them together, bury
them in the sand where they belong.
So that this planet can
be yours once more.
[deeply inhales] What
would you have us do? Huh?
What would you do, Stilgar?
I? I would... [sighs] would
strike even further north.
Then I will go further north.
And the further north you
go, the more likely it is you die.
[speaking Chakobsa]
Then I'll die.
Maybe you will too.
But the others will keep going.
And they won't stop
until the Fremen are free.
[Fedaykin fighters chattering]
He deserves to be Fedaykin.
[all agreeing]
[speaking Chakobsa]
He needs names, Stilgar.
He does!
[Stilgar] I see strength in you.
[speaking Chakobsa]
[all agreeing]
Like Usul.
The base of the pillar.
Come, come.
[man laughing]
You shall be know
among us as Usul.
- [man] Usul.
- Usul.
[Stilgar] Usul. And now,
a Fedaykin is a fighter
and needs a war name.
You must choose.
How do you call the, uh...
The small desert mouse, again?
[all laughing]
- Muad'Dib?
- [Paul] Muad'Dib.
No, no, no. [shushes]
Muad'Dib is wise in
the ways of the desert.
Muad'Dib...
[sighs] creates his own water.
The constellation that points to
the North Star, we call Muad'Dib.
"The One Who Points the Way."
That is a powerful name.
Now you are our brother. Mmm.
Paul Muad'Dib Usul.
[all cheering]
[man 1] Muad'Dib Usul.
Muad'Dib Usul.
[Paul and Stilgar laugh]
Muad'Dib Usul. Mm.
[man] Muad'Dib.
[whispers] Usul.
[shouts] Hey! Stilgar!
[Stilgar speaks
Chakobsa, laughs]
Father, I found my way.
[soft music playing]
[footsteps approaching]
[Paul] It's breathtaking.
[sighs]
[Chani] Hmm.
Look. Right there. Spice.
Arrakis is so beautiful
when the sun is low.
Where you're from, does
water really fall from the sky?
Oh, hm, yes.
Sometimes it rains
for weeks on Caladan.
Where you see sand
here, imagine water.
Our castle stands on
cliffs high above the sea.
If you dive in, you
can't reach the bottom.
- [Chani] You dive in?
- Yes, it's called swimming.
[laughs] I don't... I
don't believe you, Usul.
Usul.
What's your secret name?
Sihaya.
- Sihaya.
- Hmm.
What does that mean?
Means Desert Spring.
"Desert Spring."
- I love it.
- I hate it.
It's from some stupid prophecy.
I prefer Chani.
I prefer Chani, too, then.
Do you think Stilgar
would teach me?
- [Chani] To ride?
- [Paul] Yeah.
[Chani laughs] No.
Only Fremen ride worms.
Well, I thought I'd
become one, didn't I?
By name, not by blood.
Your blood comes from
Dukes and Great Houses.
We don't have that here.
Here, we're equal,
men and women alike.
What we do, we do
for the benefit of all.
Well, I'd very much
like to be equal to you.
Paul Muad'Dib Usul...
maybe you could be Fremen.
Maybe I'll show you the way.
[dramatic music playing]
- [gun fires]
- [explodes]
[all speaking Chakobsa]
[women screaming]
[bang]
[Baron Harkonnen] Rabban.
[tense music playing]
[breathes heavily]
[Baron Harkonnen] Fremen
attacks on your watch.
Your orders were to restore
spice production to full capacity.
Do you know what
it means if you fail?
The Emperor will take
spice out of our control.
Tighten your grip, Rabban.
[breathes heavily,
whispers] Uncle.
[Baron Harkonnen] Or
feel mine on your neck.
[breathes heavily, groans]
- [Chani] Usul? Usul.
- [Paul gasps]
It's okay. It's okay.
Hey.
I'm here, I'm here.
It's been a while since you've
had one of those nightmares.
Mm.
[Chani] Tell me,
what was it about?
[tense music playing]
[Paul] Nothing's clear.
It's only fragments.
[water drips]
I'm in the South, and
I'm following someone.
And it triggers a holy war.
Millions and millions of
people starving to death...
because of me.
[Chani] You've been exposed
to spice for a long time.
It can create weird dreams.
[breathes heavily]
It's a big day.
We can ask
Stilgar to call it off.
No. I'm fine.
[indistinct chatter]
[Stilgar] Usul.
I tuned it myself.
- Here.
- [Paul] Thanks.
[sighs]
Don't try to impress anyone.
You are brave. We all know that.
Heh? Be simple.
Be direct. Nothing fancy.
- Nothing fancy.
- Hey, I'm serious.
Nothing fancy or you
will shame my teaching.
I won't shame you. I understand.
Shai-Hulud decides today if
you become Fremen, or if you die.
[chuckles]
[Stilgar speaks Chakobsa]
Hey, Muad'Dib!
[speaking Chakobsa]
Don't embarrass us!
Call a big one!
[all laughing]
Don't worry.
Stilgar taught him well.
[Stilgar sighs]
[speaking Chakobsa]
Enough joking.
This is the final test.
[sighs]
[Paul panting]
[grunts]
[whispers] Lower.
[panting]
[grunts]
Okay. Okay.
[whirrs]
- [thumping]
- [Paul panting]
[exhales]
[panting]
[vibrating]
[gasps softly]
[all murmuring]
[speaking Chakobsa]
Not that big.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Paul panting]
[tense music playing]
[Paul] Okay.
Okay. Okay!
[shouts]
[grunts]
Come on!
Whoa!
[dramatic music playing]
[Fremen cheering in Chakobsa]
[chuckles]
You're a rider!
[yells]
[Fremen cheering]
[Paul panting]
[speaking Chakobsa]
As written.
[all chanting in Chakobsa]
[nun shouting in Chakobsa]
Reverend Mother!
Muad'Dib made peace with Shai-Hulud.
[all speaking in Chakobsa]
[nun speaking in Chakobsa]
He called a grandfather worm.
The biggest ever seen.
[all speaking in Chakobsa]
As written!
[speaking Chakobsa]
Shai-Hulud shall bow
to the Boy from the Outer World.
[all speaking in Chakobsa]
Bless the Maker and His works.
Will not Shai-Hulud know the Mahdi
when He comes?
[all speaking in Chakobsa]
Then share the Word.
[indistinct chatter]
[suspenseful music playing]
[Jessica] Mm-hmm.
Mm-hmm. I know they do.
Our task in the
North is nearly done.
They believe in Paul.
Now we go South.
There are millions of
fundamentalists there.
They will protect
him when he comes.
The Kwisatz Haderach
will be born in the South.
[both breathing heavily]
[whispering in Chakobsa]
Will you always be with me?
As long as I breathe.
What's wrong?
Chani.
There will be trouble.
What are you talking about?
Chani, what do you mean?
The way they look at you.
They worship you now.
The Fedaykin, they
count your victories.
They say you can see the future.
Whisper, " Lisan al-Gaib."
I'm no messiah.
I'm a Fedaykin of Sietch Tabr.
Yet, we have a Bene
Gesserit among us,
fanning the flames
of your legend,
saying you're the One.
[Paul sighs]
- [thumping] -
[indistinct chatter]
[Jessica] Mm.
[male Fedaykin fighter
speaking Chakobsa]
Reverend Mother!
Your palanquin is ready!
She says you should
be coming with us.
You know I can't.
She's asking why.
Because I must continue
fighting in the North,
to protect you down
there in the South.
She says she can
tell when you lie.
Tell her that's because our mother
keeps spreading dangerous tales.
[thumping continues]
What is she saying now?
She says you're blinded by love,
and she reminds you that
you must reserve your hand
for the most strategic alliance.
She's also wondering why
you don't believe in who you are.
I do believe.
I believe I matter
to these people.
And I believe I'm making
a difference in this war.
We're nearly at
the gates of the city.
- That's not what she means.
- I know what she means.
Do you not think I also feel
the weight of the prophecy?
It's not a prophecy.
It's a story that
you keep telling,
but it's not their
story, it's yours.
They deserve to be
led by one of their own.
What your people did to
this world is heartbreaking.
We gave them
something to hope for.
[shouts] That's not hope!
[male Fedaykin fighter
speaking Chakobsa]
Reverend Mother, we have to go!
[scoffs]
I'll be waiting for you.
[distorted voice] All of us.
[ancient voices
echoing] All of us.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Jessica] Those storms look bad.
[speaking Chakobsa]
They're the Guardians of the South.
It's a hard crossing,
but Shai-Hulud is strong.
[Stilgar mimicking bird]
- [machine whirring]
- [alarm blaring]
[Harkonnen soldier
speaking Harkonnen]
- [Rabban] How much?
- [Harkonnen soldier] We lost...
eighty percent of our last crop.
My Lord Rabban, you should
not leave the security perimeter.
Security perimeter? The
rats are already inside.
The Fremen Demon
might be with them.
[Rabban] I hope so.
[Harkonnen soldier] We're
tracking them, my Lord.
Today, Muad'Dib dies!
[speaking Harkonnen]
The rats are travelling fast.
Move!
[Harkonnen soldier
speaking through comm]
Where is he?
Still negative, my Lord.
[Rabban] Why do I have
to do everything myself?
Open range!
[Harkonnen soldier] Range open.
[machine beeps]
Life. Delta, delta, delta.
[Harkonnen soldier
speaking through comm]
I've lost them.
[grunts]
- Strike!
- [Harkonnen soldier] Yes, my Lord.
[machine whirring]
[Harkonnen soldiers
speaking Harkonnen]
breathing heavily]
[Harkonnen soldiers
speaking Harkonnen]
[shouts] Muad'Dib!
Show yourself! [echoes]
- [gun fires] - [Harkonnen
soldiers speaking Harkonnen]
- [grunts]
- [blade swishes]
- [breathes heavily] - [Harkonnen
soldier speaking Harkonnen]
[suspenseful music playing]
- [blade slices]
- [bodies thud]
- [grunts] - [Harkonnen
soldier speaking Harkonnen]
[Fedaykin fighters chanting]
Muad'Dib! Muad'Dib! Muad'Dib!
[dramatic music playing]
[all grunting]
- [Fedaykin fighter
yells] - [Rabban grunts]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[yells]
- [grunts] - [Fedaykin
fighter yells]
[Fedaykin fighter]
For Muad'Dib! [grunts]
[panting]
[Emperor] Muad'Dib.
Some new Fremen prophet?
[Princess Irulan] It's not the first time
we've had frictions with the Fremen.
None of this magnitude.
So, my dear daughter...
how would you deal
with this prophet?
[breathes heavily]
If this Muad'Dib
is a religious figure,
you can't use direct force.
Repression only
makes a religion flourish.
You'll only end up
humiliating yourself.
You underestimate my Sardaukar.
You underestimate
the power of faith.
[chuckles]
Her Highness proves once again
that she was my most acute student.
- You'd send assassins?
- [Princess Irulan] No.
Prophets get
stronger when they die.
Let the conflict on
Arrakis turn into war.
You then bring
peace. As a savior.
You'd be a formidable empress.
[tense music playing]
Muad'Dib. The prophet.
The one who points the way.
These are our own
religious patterns, aren't they?
This is our doing.
Muad'Dib means kangaroo mouse.
An unusual war
name for a Fremen.
- What if Paul Atreides were still alive?
- [distorted] Enough!
This must not come out. Even
to your father's ears. Understand?
I do, Reverend Mother.
[Reverend Mother Mohiam] If Paul
is alive, he likely knows the truth.
And should the
Great Houses learn
that your father was behind
the liquidation of the Atreides,
your father will face
war and lose the throne.
Then what hope is there?
Hope?
We are Bene Gesserit.
We don't hope, we plan.
Paul is not our only prospect.
The Baron's youngest nephew, Feyd-Rautha
Harkonnen, will inherit Arrakis.
He may be the answer.
Feyd-Rautha? He's psychotic.
That's irrelevant.
The question is,
can we control him?
And I intend to find out.
[suspenseful music playing]
[sighs]
[Feyd-Rautha] Would you like
some fresh meat, my darlings?
- Lungs? Or liver?
- [grunts]
[Feyd-Rautha] What would
you like? I hear they're big today.
Your new blades for
this very special day,
na-Baron, Feyd-Rautha.
[weapon master
breathing heavily]
- [blade swishes] -
[attendant chokes]
[bowl clanks]
- [attendant chokes]
- [body thuds]
- [blade stabs]
- [gasps]
[thuds]
- [Feyd-Rautha] A notch off balance.
- [harpies hiss]
[Feyd-Rautha] It's the tip.
Should be sharper.
[man struggling, grunting]
[panting]
[door opens]
[slave master] Come.
[Lanville] I won't
die like a fool.
Kill me now.
No drug for you today, Atreides.
- [crowd cheering]
- [horn blowing]
[gladiator arena announcer
speaks Harkonnen]
Under our glorious black sun,
we welcome to these special festivities
our beloved leader
Baron Vladimir Harkonnen.
[dramatic music playing]
[continuous banging]
[gladiator arena
announcer continues]
His presence today, watching over
a spectacle of blood and honor,
marks the Holy Birthday
of our beloved na-Baron, Feyd-Rautha.
[crowd cheering]
[all chanting in Harkonnen]
[continuous banging]
[Lady Margot Fenring]
Welcome to Giedi Prime, sisters.
I hope your travels
were agreeable.
[Bene Gesserit sister 1] A long way
to come just to watch our prospect
risk his life, Lady Fenring.
[Lady Margot Fenring] No fear.
These fights are all for show.
But we'll get a
good look at him.
[gladiator arena announcer
speaking Harkonnen]
[dramatic music playing]
[horn blowing]
[crowd chanting]
Feyd-Rautha! Feyd-Rautha!
[crowd cheering]
[gladiator arena announcer
speaking Harkonnen]
In celebration of our
na-Baron Feyd-Rautha,
we present a special treat.
The last three specimens
of House Atreides.
That slave isn't drugged.
That bug is walking straight.
You should cancel the fight.
Don't spoil my
nephew's birthday.
[dramatic music playing]
[breathes heavily]
[grunts]
[shouts]
[Feyd-Rautha grunts]
[both grunt, yell]
[yells]
[both grunting]
[panting]
Happy birthday, dear nephew.
[crowd cheering]
[both grunting]
[Bene Gesserit sister 2]
Why do they not stop the fight?
Plans within plans.
[suspenseful music playing]
Show me who you are.
[crowd cheering]
There he is.
[horn blows]
[picadors chittering]
[both yelling, grunting]
[panting]
[Lanville grunts]
[both yelling, grunting]
[Lanville yells in pain, groans]
Back! Back!
- [Lanville grunts] -
[Feyd-Rautha laughs]
[picadors chittering]
Stay back!
[Lanville grunting]
[whispers] You have
fought well, Atreides.
Hmm.
- [crowd cheering] -
[Feyd-Rautha grunts]
[upbeat music playing]
[crowd chanting]
Feyd-Rautha! Feyd-Rautha!
He's impressive, indeed.
[crowd chanting]
Feyd-Rautha! Feyd-Rautha!
[Feyd-Rautha] The
slave wasn't drugged.
[clicks tongue]
You tried to kill me.
This morning you were a playboy,
feared and envied,
but tonight you're a hero.
My gift to you.
I ought to drown
you in that tub.
[Baron Harkonnen laughs]
Don't be hasty.
I have another gift for you.
A bigger one.
Arrakis.
[tense music playing]
What about Rabban?
[Baron Harkonnen] He has
failed to protect spice production.
Rabban will be reassigned.
[chuckles]
Tame Arrakis, Feyd.
Free the spice. I'll
make you Emperor.
[clicks tongue] Emperor?
How?
The Emperor helped
me destroy the Atreides.
He lent his own
army to the cause.
A serious crime.
If it came to light, the Great
Houses would rise against him.
And then...
who will sit on the throne?
Feyd-Rautha Harkonnen.
[blade swishes]
You're following me.
Am I?
I may have gotten lost.
Will you show me the way out
of this maze, my Lord na-Baron?
We've met, haven't we?
I don't think so.
I'm Lady Margot Fenring.
I'm here to honor
your coming of age.
You're not allowed
in this section.
How did you get past the guards?
The guards?
[distorted] May I ask,
what are you doing here?
You're not taking part
in your own celebrations?
[breathes heavily]
[shudders] You're Bene Gesserit.
[Lady Margot Fenring] And
what makes you say that?
[Feyd-Rautha] I remember now.
I dreamed about you last night.
[Lady Margot Fenring]
A pleasant dream, I hope.
[Feyd-Rautha] Don't
mock me, woman.
[Lady Margot Fenring]
I wouldn't dare.
I know your Bene
Gesserit tricks.
And what do you know
about the Bene Gesserit?
Tell me.
Something wrong?
[Feyd-Rautha] I don't
recognize this place.
This is the guest wing.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Feyd-Rautha]
Where are you going?
To my room.
[Lady Margot Fenring
whispers] Come. To. Me.
Kneel.
[breathes heavily]
[Lady Margot Fenring whispers]
Put your right hand in the box.
[tense music playing]
[Lady Margot Fenring] A
sociopath. Of high intelligence.
Driven. Cruel.
But strongly motivated by honor.
He yearns to be hurt.
He loves pain.
[Reverend Mother Mohiam]
Can he be redeemed?
[Lady Margot Fenring]
He can be controlled.
He's sexually vulnerable.
And?
The bloodline is secured.
Female, as you requested.
You did well, Margot.
Respectfully, why didn't
you test him yourself?
I'm a motherly figure.
And based on what happened
between him and his own mother,
I didn't expect to be effective.
What happened between
him and his mother?
He murdered her.
Desire and humiliation.
Those are his levers.
If Feyd-Rautha
prevails on Arrakis,
we shall know
how to control him.
[men vocalizing]
[Giedi Prime announcer
speaking Harkonnen]
All hail na-Baron Feyd-Rautha!
The new Planetary
Governor of Arrakis!
[speaks in Harkonnen]
Rid me of this Fremen Demon.
[crowd chanting]
[dramatic music playing]
Feyd-Rautha! Feyd-Rautha!
Feyd-Rautha!
[drums beating fades out]
[suspenseful music playing]
[inhales]
[machine creaking]
[Gurney singing]
♪ Do away with these idiots ♪
♪ I blame ♪
♪ My stillsuit Is full of piss ♪
♪ My hand is caked in sand ♪
♪ Save me from
These utter morons ♪
♪ Another world, another land ♪
[man 1] We're in.
[Gurney] Juicy?
[man 1] Juicy, juicy.
[alarm beeping]
[man 1] Well, it
was nice knowing ya.
[Gurney] Oh, yeah?
Radar's clear. We're clear.
[Gurney] Cooking time.
Juicy, juicy.
[man 2 through comms]
Yeah, I got a meter reading...
[man 1 through comms] All
right, guys, worms are on their way.
- [man 2] Watch out for abrasions.
- [man 1] Get ready to dock.
[man 2] It's gonna get hot.
[man 1] Crank 'em
up! Throw them up!
[indistinct talking over comms]
[Gurney] Hold!
[breathes heavily]
Mine! Mine!
[man 1] Get moving!
[indistinct shouting]
- [man 1] East! East!
- [man 2] Get clear!
[grunts]
[man 1] Let's get out of here!
[man 2] Incoming!
[Gurney] Don't run, fight!
[man 1] We're in
deep Fremen shit.
Holy Mother.
[indistinct shouting]
[Gurney] Oh, fuck.
[Gurney grunts]
[pants heavily]
[Paul] I recognized
your footsteps...
- old man.
- [Gurney whispers] No.
[Paul chuckles]
[Fedaykin fighters
shouting in Chakobsa]
[all grunting]
[shouts command in Chakobsa]
[Fedaykin fighters
shouting in Chakobsa]
[Paul chuckles]
[panting]
- [Paul laughs]
- You young pup.
You young pup!
[panting loudly, chuckles]
[Gurney] Mmm. After
the Battle of Arrakeen,
I was able to negotiate a trip
back home for the survivors.
Thanks to these guys.
[Paul] Why'd you stay?
Well, I wanted blood.
[Paul] Rabban's head?
Mm-hmm.
Well, since Muad'Dib's
been driving Rabban crazy,
the smuggling business
has been quite profitable.
Gurney Halleck the smuggler.
[chuckles softly]
Paul Muad'Dib.
I've heard many
stories about Muad'Dib.
None of them pretty.
[whispers] You see the fear?
[Paul] When our
resources are limited...
fear is all we have.
How many men with you?
- Two hundred.
- Two hundred?
[shushes]
Do you realize what you're
able to achieve with 200 men?
Incredible fighters.
Duncan said there
were millions of them.
In the Deep South, yes.
Well, what are you waiting for?
With thousands of these guys, you
could take control of the entire planet.
It's your father's dream.
What are you afraid of?
[Chani whispers] Hey!
Worship, Gurney.
They used to be friends.
Now they're followers.
Muad'Dib, the Prophet.
Why is that a bad thing? Use it.
It's not that simple.
You have the power to avenge
your father, and you're afraid to use it?
Spice opened my mind, Gurney.
I can foresee things.
If I go South, all my
visions lead to horror.
Billions of corpses
scattered across the galaxy.
All dying because of me.
Because you lose control.
Because I gain it.
[machine whirring]
That's a lot of water.
Chani.
What? [chuckles] Look
at him, he's hopeless.
He's family.
[air hisses]
Really?
[Fremen laughing]
[Shishakli speaking Chakobsa]
What do you think of the outsider?
I think he's trouble.
[Chani speaking Chakobsa]
No, I trust Usul.
[Gurney sighs]
No need to be a prophet
to see what's ahead.
[sighs]
Your path leads to war.
You know that.
So, war is coming.
What will you do when you
feel its breath upon your neck?
[sighs heavily]
If you don't want to raise
an army in the South,
you may still have an option.
Fire power...
which you don't have.
And here I am.
I know where your father
hid the family atomics.
[Paul] Every House
possesses an atomic arsenal.
I thought ours had been lost.
It's huge, Chani. It
could change everything.
I could aim the bombs
at the main spice fields.
He who can destroy a
thing has the real control of it.
So, you can
control it and not us?
You promised me
you didn't want power.
No matter what I do,
you still don't trust me.
'Cause you're a
foreigner. Like your friend.
I'm not a foreigner.
Not to me.
But to the desert, you are.
My allegiance is to you.
To the Fremen.
I'm doing this for all of us.
Do you believe me?
I'll talk to Stilgar.
[Gurney] There.
It's right under
everybody's noses.
Not clever.
That's the idea.
Nobody would ever look in
there because it's obvious.
- Not clever.
- [chuckles]
Did you find it?
- I didn't look for it.
- [chuckles]
How many heads exactly?
Enough to blow
up the whole planet.
It's a figure of speech.
You know what I mean.
[indistinct chatter]
[suspenseful music playing]
[breathes heavily]
[panting]
[Gurney] Only with
your genetic heritage.
- [click]
- [door opening]
[tense music playing]
[Gurney] Your
great-great-grandfather's legacy.
The 92 original Atreides
family's atomic warheads.
Now that, that is power.
[Irulan] Imperial
Diary. Year 10,191.
Eighth comment.
Reports from the south
of Arrakis arrive rarely.
These are barren, burnt
lands hidden by sandstorms
which stretch a thousand
miles across the equator.
Nothing can live
there without faith.
Which is why our Bene Gesserit
missionaries have been so productive there.
Through them, we are receiving
reports of a mysterious figure
taking grip on the imaginations
of the Southern
fundamentalist tribes.
A new Reverend
Mother from the North...
spreading word of the imminent
arrival of the Lisan al-Gaib,
"The Voice from
the Outer World."
With religious fervor
rising in the South,
and Muad'Dib strangling
spice production in the North,
everything points to
the escalation of war.
[woman speaking Chakobsa]
Only one at a time...
or they fight each other to death.
How old?
Very young.
Hmm.
My daughter asks, how is it done?
Quiet.
[suspenseful music playing]
[thump]
[clicks tongue]
[worm chittering]
[speaking in Chakobsa]
The Water of Life.
Listen carefully.
Soon a man is going
to visit your temple
and he may want you
to perform the rites.
Reverend Mother,
it is forbidden.
[speaking Chakobsa]
You question the prophecy?
No man will survive.
[distorted] Let him try!
[tense music playing]
[Chani panting]
[distorted voice speaking]
[panting]
[gasps]
[gunshots in distance]
- [panting] -
[indistinct shouting]
What the hell?
Chani!
[machine creaking]
- [panting]
- [Paul] Chani!
Chani.
[both panting]
[Fremen shouting indistinctly]
Sietch Tabr.
[dramatic music playing]
[chanting in Harkonnen]
[Baron Harkonnen]
Old fashioned artillery.
Genius.
We're literally melting
rock on their heads.
I want to go on the
ground. Prepare my troops.
My Lord. I would recommend you
stay inside. There was... [chokes]
Bring his body to my quarters.
[choking]
My poor darlings are hungry.
There was no food
for them on the flight.
[Rabban] What
are you doing here?
It's early morning. What
Kiss my feet, brother.
I'm gonna eviscerate your...
[Rabban yells in pain, grunts]
[breathes heavily]
[Feyd-Rautha] You
humiliated our family.
You humiliated me.
Kiss...
- [grunts] -
[Feyd-Rautha] or die.
[kisses, panting]
We're even now.
[Baron Harkonnen] Embarrass
our family one more time...
it will be the last.
[dramatic music playing]
[woman screaming]
[indistinct talking in Chakobsa]
[woman crying,
speaking in Chakobsa]
They're all dead!
I lost them all in the fire!
[Stilgar] They didn't even
engage on the ground,
like honorable fighters.
[Shishakli speaking Chakobsa]
[man on radio speaking Chakobsa]
The whole of the North has been hit.
[Shishakli speaking Chakobsa]
There is a call for a war council
in the South.
Every leader must attend.
[exhales heavily]
Muad'Dib, they're waiting for you.
[tense music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
Usul, in the South...
only leaders are
allowed to speak.
- You must take my place.
- I can't do that.
It is a good time to
cross blades with me.
I am weak. I am an
easy kill, Muad'Dib.
I'd rather cut off my own hand.
We need you. We need the
Lisan al-Gaib to lead our people.
You know what I
think of all that, Stilgar.
I don't care what
you believe. I believe.
[tense music playing]
[clanking]
I didn't see it coming.
The Harkonnens aren't done here.
They just went back to reload.
We're setting thumpers.
We're moving
everyone to the South.
I'll stay behind and
cover your retreat.
- What are you talking about?
- Chani, I can't go with you.
You know why.
- [Gurney] I'll stay, too.
- Nobody stays but me.
- [Gurney] Paul.
- That's an order, Gurney Halleck! Go South!
Protect my mother.
- My Lord.
- [Shishakli] Muad'Dib.
[speaking Chakobsa]
None of these people
will leave without you.
I can't go South.
He's afraid of the
fundamentalists.
And he should be.
[ancient voices
whispering indistinctly]
[ancient voice 1] Don't resist.
[distorted growling]
Talk to me, Jamis.
[ancient voices
whispering indistinctly]
[ancient voice 2] You
see only fragments.
You cannot see the future
without seeing the past.
To unlock your mind, you
need to drink the Water of Life...
and you will see everything.
[tremors]
[Jamis] A good hunter always
climbs the highest dune before his hunt.
He needs to see...
as far as he can see.
You need to see.
[Jessica] You must
drink the Water of Life.
Your mind, it's gonna open,
and you will see.
The world has
made choices for us.
If I go South, I might lose you.
You will never lose me,
Paul Atreides.
Not as long as you
stay who you are.
I'll cross the storms with you.
Go South.
Bring your people to safety.
And then I will do
what must be done.
- [whooshing]
- [screeching]
Where?
Spy. Left behind.
No trace of the others.
[Feyd-Rautha] They've gone
South to hide in the storms.
Send this message to the Baron.
The North is
liberated and secured.
Harvest spice at will.
Yes, na-Baron.
[commander speaking Harkonnen]
You killed nine of my
men with one single blade.
[scoffs]
[translator] She won't talk.
[Feyd-Rautha]
Tell her that's fine.
I already know
everything I need to know.
Only pleasure remains.
[rumbling]
[rustling]
[Maker Keeper speaking Chakobsa]
You're not allowed in here, stranger.
Leave or die.
I should be welcomed...
If you drink, you shall die.
If you drink, you may see.
[ancient voices
speaking Chakobsa]
[ancient voice] Now
that you can see our past,
you can see your future.
[waves crashing]
[Alia] Oh, brother,
my dearest brother,
you are not prepared
for what is to come.
You'll now learn the
truth about our family.
And it will hurt
you to the core.
Paul...
Don't worry. I'm with you.
I love you.
[speaking Chakobsa]
Who knows about this?
Only you, Reverend Mother.
Good.
Where are the others?
[guard speaking]
They just arrived from the North.
[distorted] Find them.
[whirring]
[panting]
[crowd murmuring in Chakobsa]
[gasps]
[Chani] Paul?
Paul.
I'm here. I'm here. Hey.
[gasps softly]
[shouts] What happened?
What happened?
He's dead.
His vital signs are so
low, they can't be detected.
But he's alive.
What did you do to him?
No, not that. Why
would he do that?
Why would you do that?
[speaking Chakobsa]
Because He is the One.
The Lisan al-Gaib should find His way
to where no man has ever been.
Chani, his body is fighting the
poison and he needs your help.
You're insane!
You do it.
You did this to him.
You did this to your own son!
You do it!
Fix it yourself.
Chani, you might not believe in
the prophecy, but you're a part of it.
[Chani] You're the poison.
You and your lies.
Why would you do this?
[distorted] Do it.
[speaking Chakobsa]
He shall come back from the dead
with Desert Spring tears.
Bring me a drop of Water of Life.
[crowd speaking Chakobsa]
As written.
[whispers] Desert Spring tears.
[ancient voice]
Kwisatz Haderach,
climb up. Arise.
[gasps]
[chuckles]
Usul, I'm here. I'm here.
[sighs]
[crowd murmurs]
[Chani whispers] Are you okay?
Yes.
[Paul breathing heavily]
Are you sure?
[breathing heavily]
Thanks to you.
[sighs]
[breathing heavily]
[Chani grunts]
[Jessica] I'm sorry about Chani.
She'll come to understand.
I've seen it.
[whispers] You can see?
The visions are clear now.
I see possible
futures. All at once.
Our enemies are all around us.
And in so many
futures, they prevail.
But I do see a way.
There is a narrow way through.
I saw our bloodline, Mother.
Written across time.
[cooing]
You are the daughter of
Baron Vladimir Harkonnen.
Did my father know?
I didn't know myself, until
I took the worm's poison.
We're Harkonnens.
[sighs]
So this is how we'll survive.
By being Harkonnens.
[crashing, rumbling]
[deep clicking]
[man chanting in Chakobsa]
[crowd chanting]
[man chanting]
We must talk.
Stilgar, you can stop
this. Do you hear me?
You have the power to stop this.
Northern woman!
You are not allowed to
speak inside the circle.
If you want to speak,
you know what to do.
Stilgar, please.
For Arrakis' sake.
[man chanting]
[scoffs]
[crowd chanting]
[crowd murmuring]
This prophecy is
how they enslave us!
How they dominate... [groans]
You'll get yourself in trouble.
This is none of your business.
Rabban Harkonnen
himself killed my family.
He gave me this scar
to remember him by.
This is all of my business.
[horns blowing]
[crowd murmuring]
[murmuring intensifies]
[crowd exclaiming]
[speaking Chakobsa]
Only tribe leaders can speak.
If you wish to share your voice,
you must take his
place by defeating him
and returning his
water to the well.
You think I'm stupid enough to
deprive myself of the best of us?
[shouts in Chakobsa]
Do you smash a knife
before battle?
Take my life, Usul.
It is the only way.
I'm pointing the way!
[crowd murmuring]
[whispers] Slow down.
[shouting in Chakobsa]
There is no one in this room
who can stand against me!
[crowd clamoring]
Your mothers warned you
about my coming!
Fear the moment.
[silence]
But you think you
could have a chance.
[speaking Chakobsa]
But you're afraid.
What if I could be the One?
This could be the moment you've been
praying for, all your life.
You're praying now,
to your grandmother.
She died nine moons ago.
She lost an eye.
A rock smashed her face
as she was crossing the Belt.
She was 12 when it happened.
At that time, this world
had a Fremen name.
Dune.
Lisan al-Gaib!
[crowd chanting] Lisan
al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
[speaking Chakobsa]
Lisan al-Gaib!
[shouting in Chakobsa]
In your nightmares,
you give water to the dead,
and it brings joy to your heart!
[crying] Muad'Dib!
[crowd chanting] Muad'Dib.
[groans]
[Stilgar speaking Chakobsa]
Mahdi, what do you foresee for us?
[speaking Chakobsa]
Green Paradise.
[crowd exclaiming]
Lisan al-Gaib, show us the Way!
This is my father's
ducal signet.
[gasps softly]
[yelling] I am Paul
Muad'Dib Atreides,
Duke of Arrakis.
[speaking Chakobsa]
The Hand of God be my witness!
I am the Voice from the Outer World!
I will lead you to paradise!
- [crowd cheers]
- Lisan al-Gaib!
[crowd chanting] Lisan
al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
Lisan al-Gaib!
[breathes deeply]
[Irulan] Paul
Atreides is still alive.
He challenges my father.
You've never been on Arrakis.
It's quite impressive.
You'll see.
Was this all upon your advice?
What?
Did you counsel my father
to exterminate the Atreides?
Of course I did. Why else
would it have happened?
You tried to sacrifice
an entire bloodline.
And I was right to do it.
The Kwisatz Haderach
is a form of power
that our world has not yet seen.
The ultimate power.
For ninety generations,
we have supervised
House Atreides.
They were promising, but they
were becoming dangerously defiant.
Their bloodline had
to be terminated.
That is why we have put
many bloodlines at work.
Several prospects.
But it's backfired.
Paul is alive.
And if he defeats
Feyd-Rautha, my father...
Your father will lose the
throne no matter who prevails.
But there is one way your
family can remain in power
and, through you, the
continuation of our stewardship.
One. Way.
Are you prepared?
You've been preparing me
my whole life, Reverend Mother.
You're heading
north with the others?
I'm Fedaykin.
I follow my leaders. If
fighting goes north, I go north.
Paul didn't have
a choice, Chani.
I won't be fighting for him.
I'm fighting for my people.
I came to wish you best of luck.
I'd wish you the same,
but it seems you've
won your battle.
[whooshing]
[Gurney] He took the bait.
[Paul] Oh, the
Emperor's very obliging.
He's right on time.
[speaking Chakobsa]
As you foresaw, Muad'Dib...
a great-grandmother of a storm.
[whooshing]
What is he doing here?
I brought spice
production under control.
What do we do?
Send messages to
the Great Houses.
Tell them that Arrakis is
under Sardaukar attack.
Tell them, their future
hangs in the balance.
[whispering in Chakobsa]
He brought his whole army.
[Paul] When the
storm hits this ridge,
Gurney will open the
way for you, Stilgar,
so you can enter the
basin from the West
and distract their
defense systems.
Chani, I want you
and your Fedaykin
to then attack from the East,
inside the basin.
I'll strike from the
North, head on,
with the Fundamentalist troops.
And I'll serve
Arrakeen for dessert.
Remember, I need
the Emperor alive.
[speaking Chakobsa]
Long live the fighters.
[all repeat]
[indistinct chatter]
[whirring, hissing]
[machine whirring, hissing]
Hm.
[breathing heavily]
[Emperor] Baron,
do you have any idea who
this Muad'Dib could be?
Some fanatic, your
Majesty. That's all we know.
More. More. Give me more.
He's a madman!
- Mad?
- All Fremen are mad.
[scoffing] That's all you know?
Really?
[Feyd-Rautha] Muad'Dib is dead.
Or he went hiding in
the Southern storms
which means the same thing.
[signing]
They speak the truth.
[Bashar] Your Majesty,
the sand storm
that's approaching
threatens the
integrity of our shields.
We recommend
going back into orbit.
Well, the mountains will
protect us from most of it,
your Majesty.
Baron, have you
ever investigated
the south regions of Arrakis?
Well, the entire
region is uninhabitable.
It's well known, your Majesty.
[Emperor] Your uninhabited South
exhibits evidence
of human activity.
[Baron] I wasn't aware of this.
I swear to you, I wasn't
aware of any of this.
[Baron gasping]
- [groans]
- [gasps]
[Emperor] Muad'Dib is alive.
I must find him.
[breathing heavily]
[flags fluttering]
[whooshing]
[thumping, clicking]
[crowd cheering]
[shouting in Chakobsa]
Long live the fighters!
[crowd repeats in unison]
Fire!
[missiles whooshing]
[explosions]
[rumbling]
[crashing]
- [clattering] -
[Irulan gasping]
[crashing]
[Bashar] Sardaukar! On guard!
[Baron groaning]
[metal creaking]
[crashing in distance]
[rustling]
[crumbling]
[blades unsheathe]
[breathing heavily]
[wind whooshing]
[officer shouts in Galach]
[whooshing]
- [soldiers panting]
- [blades unsheathe]
[rattling, deep clicking]
[bellowing]
[Sardaukar screaming]
[Fremen shouting]
[Stilgar speaks Chakobsa]
[Fremen fighters
shout in Chakobsa]
[panicked shouting]
[Fremen fighters
speaking Chakobsa]
[Fremen fighters yelling]
[Chani speaks Chakobsa]
[Fedaykin fighters
speaking Chakobsa]
[all shouting]
[Chani grunting]
[soldiers grunt]
[Baron gasping]
[loud thud]
[soldiers clamoring]
[Bashar screams] Sardaukar!
Grandfather.
You die like an animal.
Muad'Dib.
[speaking Chakobsa]
Bring the prisoners to the Residency.
Kill the Sardaukar.
Give the Baron's body to the desert.
[breathes heavily]
[Fedaykin leader
speaking Chakobsa]
[Fremen fighters
chanting in Chakobsa]
[all soldiers shouting]
[grunting]
[Gurney] Rabban!
Look who's back from the dead.
[grunts]
[chokes]
[gasping]
For my Duke, and my friends.
[indistinct chatter]
[Chani speaks Chakobsa]
[Stilgar] Warships.
The Great Houses.
Gurney, it's time.
Bring the prisoners.
- My Lord.
- [Stilgar speaks Chakobsa]
[speaks Chakobsa]
This isn't over yet.
I want you to know...
I will love you as
long as I breathe.
[sighs]
[door opens]
[breathes deeply]
There is a massed
armada in orbit.
You're facing a full
invasion, Fremen.
[Paul] How can you be so sure
the Great Houses are here for me?
They may be curious to hear my
side of the story, don't you think?
I am Paul Atreides, son of
Leto Atreides, Duke of Arrakis.
- Gurney.
- My Lord.
Send a warning to all ships.
If the Great Houses attack, our
atomics will obliterate all spice fields.
- You're out of your mind.
- He's bluffing.
Consider what you're
about to do, Paul Atreides.
- [distorted] Silence!
- [Reverend Mother Mohiam gasps]
[shudders]
[whispering] Abomination.
Message sent, my Lord.
As a servant of the Imperium,
you will bow at my feet.
Your feet? You'll be
lucky to keep your head.
I'll take the hand
of your daughter.
She will remain safe.
And we will rule
together over the Empire.
- [crowd chattering]
- [breathes heavily]
[Paul] But you...
You have to
answer for my father.
Do you know why I killed him?
Because he was a man
who believed in the
rules of the heart.
But the heart is
not meant to rule.
In other words...
your father was a weak man.
Stand or choose your champion.
[Feyd-Rautha] I
am here, Atreides.
I need a blade.
Accept mine.
Do not stain your
hands on this animal.
Let me deal with him.
It's my burden, Gurney.
[Feyd-Rautha exhales]
Why does he take such risks?
Muad'Dib leads the way.
[speaking Chakobsa]
I'm happy to finally
meet you, cousin.
Cousin? Is that right?
Well, you wouldn't be
the first relative I've killed.
May thy knife chip and shatter.
[chuckles softly] May
thy knife chip and shatter.
[both grunting]
[crowd gasps]
[panting]
- She's your pet?
- [breathes heavily]
Any special
attention for the pet?
[breathes heavily]
[both grunting]
[crowd gasps]
[Feyd-Rautha yells]
[Paul grunts]
[Paul grunting, panting]
[panting]
[grunting]
- [Feyd-Rautha
grunts] - [Paul panting]
[both grunting, panting]
You have fought well, Atreides.
[panting]
[Paul yells]
Lisan al-Gaib!
[Fremen chanting] Lisan
al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
[sighs]
[panting]
[Paul groaning]
[yells]
[Jessica] You
should've believed.
You chose the wrong side.
[Reverend Mother Mohiam] Side?
You, of all people, should know.
There are no sides...
Reverend Mother.
The life debt has been paid.
Spare my father now and
I will be your willing bride.
The throne will be yours.
[breathes heavily]
[stomps]
[inhales deeply]
My Lord,
the Great Houses have answered.
They refuse
to honor your ascendancy.
We await your orders,
Lisan al-Gaib.
Lead them to Paradise.
[female Fremen] Lisan al-Gaib!
[all chanting]
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
[speaking Chakobsa]
[all chanting]
Lisan al-Gaib! Lisan al-Gaib!
[Alia]
What is happening, Mother?
Your brother attacks
the Great Houses.
The Holy War begins.
[breathing heavily]